<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<div>
    <p>Welcome to the Bishopston Planning Portal, our innovative interactive tool presenting details
        of the main planning applications in our area lodged recently with Bristol City Council as
        the local planning authority. </p>
    <h3>Map</h3>
    <ul>
        <li>The Google map shows (crudely) the boundaries of the Bishopston area we typically work
            in, though some planning applications outside the immediate area that impinge on us also
            appear. </li>
        <li>Click on a pin, using the legend provided, to find out the address and basic details of
            any planning application. </li>
        <li>You’ll see The Bishopston Society’s summary comments and our response to the
            application. </li>
        <li>You’ll also see the application reference number, which is linked to the application
            details (see below). </li>
    </ul>
    <h3>List</h3>
    <ul>
        <li>Recent planning applications are listed here in tabular format, initially in descending order of validation date, ie the date the application was checked and validated by BCC </li>
        <li>Applications can be sorted into a different order using the up/down buttons in each
            column heading. </li>
        <li>The application reference number is again linked to the application details. </li>
    </ul>
    <h3>Search</h3>
    <ul>
        <li>If the application you are looking for is not visible via Map or List, use the Search
            function to get a shorter list.</li>
    </ul>
    <h3>Application details </h3>
    <ul>
        <li>Lots more details are provided on the application details screen, including a close-up
            map, the current status of the application, our comments, and those made by the public. </li>
        <li>You can use the link provided to reach all the official documents for the application on
            Bristol City Council’s web site. You can also submit your own comments via this web
            site. </li>
    </ul>
    <h3>Scope and maintenance</h3>
    <ul>
        <li>This portal covers all planning applications in our area lodged with Bristol City
            Council since October 2017. </li>
        <li>The data is updated every day.</li>
    </ul>
    <h3>About TBS comments &amp; recommendations</h3>
    <ul>
        <li>The Bishopston Society’s policy on planning applications is documented here and
            reviewed/updated from time to time by the committee, with routine decision-making
            delegated to our planning team. </li>
        <li>We also consult our membership and disseminate our policy via our web site, newsletter,
            email updates, social media channels, etc., especially in response to changes in the
            policy environment, and when larger developments crop up. </li>
    </ul>
    <h3>About this portal </h3>
    <ul>
        <li>This portal has been developed by&#160;<a target="_blank" class="external" href="http://kitwallace.co.uk">Chris Wallace</a> as part of a project to analyse
            Bristol City Council planning applications. </li>
        <li>The data presented is drawn primarily from Bristol City Council’s <a target="_blank" class="external" href=" http://planningonline.bristol.gov.uk/online-applications/">searchable planning database</a> , with value-added content added by the TBS team. </li>
        <li>Technically-minded readers may wish to know that it uses&#160;the <a href="http://existdb.org"> eXist open source XML database</a> and is programmed in
            XQuery and Javascript. Issues and eventually code reside on <a target="_blank" class="external" href="https://github.com/KitWallace/planningapplications">Github</a>. </li>
    </ul>
    <h3>Feedback</h3>
    <ul>
        <li>Comments and feedback on this portal are welcome via <a href="http://bishopstonsociety.org.uk/about/contactus">our contact form</a>.</li>
    </ul>
    <h3> Disclaimer</h3>
    <ul>
        <li>Whilst we have confidence in the software and data used in the construction of this
            portal, we offer no warranty over the veracity or accuracy of the information provided,
            and are not liable for any errors or inaccuracies you may encounter. Our standard legal
            notices and policies may be viewed at
            http://bishopstonsociety.org.uk/legal-notices.</li>
    </ul>
    <h3>Admin</h3>
    <ul>
        <li>
            <a href="admin/menu">Admin functions </a>
        </li>
    </ul>
</div>